[Music]
the Pythagorean theorem is one of the
most well-known theorems in the history
of mankind it states that for any right
triangle a s + B2 is equal to c^2 most
people have seen this theorem but not
that many actually know the reason why
it's true today we're showing just that
to do this we take four copies of any
right triangle as shown here and then we
flip them to create the following image
then we want to arrange them in a way
like so to form a
square notice that the angles shown here
are complimentary so that the
intersection of the red lines actually
form 90° angles as shown
below now we have a red square basically
inscribed within a larger blue and green
square let's go further by asking what's
the area of the blue and green green
square the area of the blue and green
square can be given by its side lengths
so the side lengths are a plus b so the
area is a + b^ 2 which is equal to a 2 +
2 a + b
2 but alternatively we could have also
found the area from our figure by
noticing that the area is just four
copies of the area of each right
triangle plus the area of the Red Square
Square so now we have two alternative
definitions for the area of the large
blue and green square and we write it
below as shown
here now it just remains for us to
algebraically simplify this in the
following fashion and then to notice
that if we just subtract
2ab from both sides and do a little bit
of algebra we have exactly that a 2 + B2
is equal to C squ and this holds for any
generic right triangle I hope that's
shown some of the beauty behind the
mathematical proof of Pythagoras's
Theorem and actually showing you some of
the intuition and reasoning behind this
beautiful and very well-known
mathematical theorem thank you for
watching
[Music]